There are those who sweep and those who pay others to sweep.
The Door is a drama film directed by István Szabó.
Emerenc, an elderly and private woman, is hired to be the
housekeeper of a struggling writer, Magda.
An event in the writer's life prompts Emerenc to disclose details of her
traumatizing past, which will bond the two women forever.
Based on the novel by Magda Szabó.
Emerenc Szeredás, played by Helen Mirren.
Magda, played by Martina Gedeck.
Tibor, played by Károly Eperjes.
Mr. Brodarics, played by Péter Andorai.
Sutu, played by Enikő Börcsök.
The Lt. Colonel, played by Gábor Koncz.
The Door (Hungarian: Az ajtó) is a 2012 English-language Hungarian drama film
directed by István Szabó and starring Martina Gedeck and Helen Mirren.
It is based on the Hungarian novel of the same name concerning the relationship of a
novelist (Gedeck) and her eccentric maid (Mirren) in early-1970s Hungary.
The film was selected to be featured in the competition programme
at the 34th Moscow International Film Festival.
It also won the Michael Curtiz Audience Award at the Hungarian
Film Festival of Los Angeles in November 2012.
The film explores themes of budapest, hungary,
cat, married couple, author, maid.
The tone is emotional.